PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Experienced Mathematics Tutor with a demonstrated history of working in the higher education industry. Over two years of experience managing and operating a convenience store. worked on multiple team coding projects. Skilled in Python, C++, Java, JavaScript, React.js, Android Development, and web applications. Computer Science Junior at UC Irvine. Open for Summer 2019 internship opportunities.

EDUCATIONALBACKGROUND

B.S COMPUTER SCIENCE

University of California, Irvine

September 2018 - June 2020

Relevant Coursework: Information retrieval, Database management,

Concepts programming languages

ASSOCIATE DEGREE - COMPUTER SCIENCE

Orange Coast College

June 2016 - May 2018

Costa Mesa, CA, US

Relevant Coursework: Data structure and Algorithms, Discrete Math, Boolean Algebra, Calculus Single-Variable, Calculus Multivariable, Computer Architecture, Intro to Software Engineering, C++, and Java

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Coding: C++, Java, Python, Javascript (jQuery, React.js, Node.js), HTML, CSS, SQLite, XML.

Technologies/Environments: Linux, Android Studio, Git & Github

M.ANAS(Jason) Alaya

Computer Science

GitHub: https://github.com/pistachio05

Contact Number: 657-271-7582 Email Address: malaya@uci.edu

Projects

Ant Almanac(Summer 18)

- Web application to help UCI Anteaters with scheduling and course planning.
- Team project follows Agile development methodologies.
- Technologies: Node.js, React.js, Material-UI, Python, MongoDB, HTML, CSS.
- Project Repository: https://github.com/the-rango/AntAlmanac/tree/react

TravelAid (Spring 2018)

- Open source project in Java. Provides info about countries for travelers.
- Object-Oriented Design: Encapsulation, Inheritance, and Polymorphism.
- JavaFx, Scene builder, Lambda Expressions, Send an automated Email.
- Project Repository: https://github.com/pistachio05/TravelAid

Class Schedule Program (Spring 17)

- Built a program to search for and display classes in a school system.
- Implemented C++ linked list to store and sort course objects.
- Utilized pointers and dynamic memory to optimize performance.

EMPLOYMENT EXPERIENCE

CSU Fullerton

Academic Researcher - Summer 2017

Participated in a research project at the CSUF computer network security lab. The project analyzed DOS and DDOS threats on a software-defined network (SDN), and discussed mitigation strategies. Built a virtual SDN using FloodLight open source controller, Mininet a network emulator, and sFlow traffic monitoring tool.

Golden West College

Math Tutor - September 2016 to current

Improve students critical thinking and problem-solving skills. Encourage students to ask questions and develop interest in the subject matter. Conducted tutoring sessions for both individuals and groups of 4-5 students.

Valero

Store Manager - March 2014 to current

Supervise and manage store operations, handle various forms of payments and customer relations
Resolve customer complaints and technical difficulties